Contato

61 991319712 (Mobile) alvino.digo@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ alvinorodrigues (LinkedIn) alvinodigo.github.io/ (Portfolio)

Principais competências

jQuery Acessibilidade Semantic HTML

Languages Inglês

Alvino Rodrigues

Desenvolvedor Front-end na IBICT - Instituto Brasileiro de Informação em Ciência e Tecnologia

Ceilândia, Distrito Federal, Brasil

Resumo

I am a frontend developer and my job consists of support the teams I belong to in order to transform ideas and solutions into rich and light interfaces, so that the user can have a really satisfying and effective experience. My goal is not only to make these interfaces easy to understand and to use, but also to meet user's expectations and achieve business objectives.

I'm interested in the product's accessibility and in the users' satisfaction. I am the one who ensures the projects' responsiveness, since "screens" are no longer limited only to smartphones, tablets or desktops.

Among the clients in the projects I've worked for are: Caixa Econômica Federal, Embrapa - Brazilian Agricultural Research Corporation, SEBRAE, the Ministry of Tourism, the Ministry of Education, the Federal District Government, the CNA - Confederation of Agriculture and Livestock of Brazil, FUNCEF, MDIC - Ministry of Development, Industry and Foreign Trade, Brasília Shopping, CGU - Comptroller General of Brazil, among others.

I also taught frontend classes and gave training to IT staff. Some of the languages, concepts and techniques I work with are: XHTML, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, LESS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, JSON, D3JS, PHP, Wordpress, SEO, Git, Web Standards, Performance, Cross-Browser Interfaces, Accessibility, Usability, Responsive Design, Grunt, Gulp, Angular, among others.

Experiência

IBICT - Instituto Brasileiro de Informação em Ciência e Tecnologia Desenvolvedor Front-end agosto de 2018 - Present

Brasília

DOT digital group Front-end Developer agosto de 2008 - novembro de 2017 (9 anos 4 meses)

Faculdade Santa Teresinha Auxiliar de Informática 2005 - 2008 (3 anos) Taguatinga - DF

Forseti Programador 2004 - 2005 (1 ano) Guarulhos - SP

INFRAERO Estagiário 2001 - 2002 (1 ano) Aeroporto de Guarulhos - SP

Formação acadêmica

Centro Universitário Euro-Americano – UNIEURO Analista de Sistemas, Tecnologia da informação · (2009 - 2013)

Escola Técnica Professor Horácio Augusto da Silveira Industrial, Tecnologia · (1997 - 1999)